An unconventional love story...
The Lobster is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Yorgos Lanthimos.
In a dystopian near future, single people, according to the laws of The City, are taken to The Hotel, where they are obliged
to find a romantic partner in forty-five days or are transformed into animals and sent off into The Woods.
David, played by Colin Farrell.
Short Sighted Woman, played by Rachel Weisz.
Hotel Manager, played by Olivia Colman.
Loner Leader, played by Léa Seydoux.
Loner Swimmer, played by Michael Smiley.
The Maid, played by Ariane Labed.
The Lobster is a 2015 absurdist black comedy-drama art film directed and co-produced by
Yorgos Lanthimos, from a screenplay by Lanthimos and Efthimis Filippou.
It stars Colin Farrell, Rachel Weisz, Jessica Barden, Olivia Colman,
Ashley Jensen, Ariane Labed, Angeliki Papoulia, John C.
Reilly, Léa Seydoux, Michael Smiley, and Ben Whishaw.
The film follows a newly single bachelor who moves into a hotel with other singles, who are all obliged to
find a romantic partner within 45 days; otherwise, they’ll be transformed into animals.
The film was announced in October 2013, with Jason
Clarke originally cast in the lead role.
After Clarke left production, Farrell replaced him by February 2014, with
Weisz also joining the cast after Elizabeth Olsen dropped out.
The rest of the cast was rounded out by March as principal
photography began, which concluded in May.
Filming largely took place in Dublin and County Kerry.
The film is a co-production by Ireland, the United
Kingdom, Greece, France, and the Netherlands.
The Lobster premiered at the 2015 Cannes Film Festival on 15 May, where
it competed for the Palme d'Or and won the Jury Prize.
It was theatrically released in the United Kingdom on 16 October
2015, grossing $18 million on a $4 million budget.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for its screenplay, humor, originality, and thematic content, and was nominated for
Best Original Screenplay at the 89th Academy Awards and for Outstanding British Film at the 69th British Academy Film Awards.
The film explores themes of hotel, suicide attempt, boat, dystopia, woods.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.